



Valentin Micu

Nationality: Romanian

(+40) 723056230

Date of birth: 03/12/1976

Gender: Male

■ Email address: <u>valvic6@gmail.com</u>

Website: https://github.com/valvic66

• Address: Constanța (Romania)

ABOUT ME

After ending 16 years in the previous job and being very passionate about everything involving programming and THE WEB, I started the journey of becoming a professional web engineer. Since then, I'm definitely in love with it ALL:)

I am a very organized person, committed to work, a team player with great self learning abilities.

I love all kinds of sports, especially skating and hiking our beautiful mountains. Very fond of reading tech books but fiction as well. Can not resist any escape in nature.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Engineeer

Cognizant Softvision / FAR / Estee Lauder [10/2019 - Current]

City: Constanta, RO Full remote for SV

- Continued working for Estee Lauder Beauty Company.
- Started mentoring junior developers.
- Got included into interview process for hiring new developers, which is awesome and challanging.
- Worked in paralel for Cognizant Softvision on new project named Furniture Augmented Reality in React Native and AI (wanted to tackle for a long time mobile development)
- Developed the app, did a lot of refactoring and bug fixes. Direct communication with the client. Performed demos to the client.

Web Engineer

Softvision / Estee Lauder [01/2019 - 10/2019]

City: Bucharest, RO

- Continued working for Estee Lauder Beauty Company and their challenging E-commerce Websites.
- Got promoted as Web Engineer.

Web Developer

Softvision / Estee Lauder [02/2018 - 01/2019]

City: Bucharest, RO

- Started a challenging E-commerce for Estee Lauder Beauty Company with the following stack: ReactJS and TypeScript, Storybook and Lerna as development environment, MobX for state management, styled-components and grid-styled for components CSS, Jest and React Enzyme for testing.
- Provided development and maintenance for all Estee Lauder managed sites as Clinique, Jomalone, Glamglow, Smashbox, Dr, Jart ... (plus a lot of more beauty brands).
- Created Genie, a site that fits all the brands' need with possibility to be styled differently as required.
- Agile team, fixed production bugs, performed pushes to prod and lower environments, performed demos to the client on a weekly basis and kept direct communication with the client.

Web Developer

Freelancer [09/2017 - 02/2018]

City: Remote

- Created React custom components for a web application platform designed to find jobs by recommendations. Started using Feathers REST. Implemented Redux in some of the custom components. Used Reactstrap components based on Bootstrap4 flex implementation. Used Underscore Js to change and polish data structure.
- Created React custom component for a local real estate company. Used React DnD module.
- Created different custom components for different remote clients and implementation of the component API. to their web sites / applications.
- Started using Vue Js for a project in collaboration with Constanta Web Developers.
- Different remote React JS and Vue Js projects.
- Completed my presentation site: https://valvic66.github.io/website3/#/

Full-Stack JavaScript Developer

Zen Code Entreprise [03/2017 - 09/2017]

City: Constanta, RO

Started my own media Company.

- Created company site in React, using Redux as state management.
- Created company site back end in Node JS using Express framework and Mongo Database.
- Lots of projects for internal / external clients in Wordpress and React.

Web Developer

BLike Development [09/2016 - 03/2017]

City: Constanta, RO

- Designed and improved company site.
- Fully reconstructed front end and added mobile responsiveness in Bootstrap to a transportation company web application (Kirvad Tour).
- Improved my own Vanilla JS and jQuery skills.
- Created the front end in React for a harbour cargo storage company web application. Worked for the first time with Redux state management.

Web Developer

CERONAV (Romanian Maritime Training Centre) [01/2016 - 09/2016]

City: Constanta, RO

- Built and improved company own sites (internal and client exposed ones).
- Improved design for course programming site (the site used for clients to book the courses).
- Designed and improved Moodle testing sites for different expert trainers.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Online Courses and Certifications

Cognizant Udemy Business, freeCodeCamp, Web Camp [2019 - 2022]

Web Academy training

Cognizant Softvision / Estee Lauder [02/2018 - 08/2018]

Master on comercial vessels for VShips Germany

[2000 - 2016]

Maritime Academy "Mircea cel Batran"

[06/1995 - 06/2000]

Military High School "Alexandru Ioan Cuza"

[06/1990 - 06/1995]

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

DIGITAL SKILLS

Agile Metodology / Git / HTML & CSS / JavaScript / React / React Native / C# / Vue JS

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: AM **Driving Licence:** B